<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pavel Derendyaev test</title>
    <link>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Pavel Derendyaev test</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 19:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.dddpaul.pw/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bind interfaces to multiple zones with Firewalld on CentOS-7</title>
      <link>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/2018/06/24/firewalld-zones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/2018/06/24/firewalld-zones/</guid>
      <description>As you can expect from man firewall-cmd interface binding to zone other than default (public) could be achieved with the following command sequence:
firewall-cmd --zone public --remove-interface eth1 --permanent firewall-cmd --zone internal --add-interface eth1 --permanent firewall-cmd --reload  Seems like it&amp;rsquo;s done:
firewall-cmd --get-zone-of-interface=eth1 internal  But after firewalld restart or server reboot things aren&amp;rsquo;t so bright:
firewall-cmd --get-zone-of-interface=eth1 public  The reason is in this CentOS-7 bug. The only workaround is to specify zone in /etc/sysconfig/network-scripts/ifcfg-eth1 file:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker network and Swarm mode links</title>
      <link>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/2018/06/24/docker-network-swarm-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/2018/06/24/docker-network-swarm-links/</guid>
      <description>Some useful articles &amp;amp; videos about modern networking in Docker:
 Macvlan Driver - Docker Macvlan driver is out of experimental in Docker 1.12. Configuring Macvlan and Ipvlan Linux Networking - What Docker Macvlan driver does under the hood. Materials for 2016 DevOps Networking Forum (DNF) Presentation - Slides about Docker networking with Ansible playbooks. Видео докладов с Docker митапа - Особо интересен доклад Константина Назарова &amp;ldquo;Каждому контейнеру по IP&amp;rdquo; (на русском).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker registry on Centos 7</title>
      <link>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/2018/06/24/docker-registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/2018/06/24/docker-registry/</guid>
      <description>1. Create logical volumes for direct-lvm production mode
Assume that we have 40 GByte block device named as /dev/sdb with one full-size Linux partition on it.
Official Device Mapper storage driver guide recommends to use thin pools now. Use these commands to create thin-provisioned logical volumes:
pvcreate /dev/sdb1 # Create physical volume vgcreate docker /dev/sdb1 # Create volume group and add this physical volume to it # Create logical volumes lvcreate --wipesignatures y -n data docker -l 40%VG lvcreate --wipesignatures y -n registry docker -l 40%VG lvcreate --wipesignatures y -n metadata docker -l 2%VG # Convert data volume to thin pool&amp;#39;s data volume lvconvert -y --zero n -c 512K --thinpool docker/data --poolmetadata docker/metadata # Set thin pool autoextend features cat &amp;gt; /etc/lvm/profile/docker-data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java network listeners</title>
      <link>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/2018/06/24/java-listeners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/2018/06/24/java-listeners/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written a small listeners library today. It allows to create Callables which can be submitted to ExecutorService. The callable itself implements creating server socket and binding it to local port.
There two principal type of listeners: blocking and non-blocking (thanks to Java NIO.
Blocking listener is very simple but in can&amp;rsquo;t be interrupted by calling thread. So there&amp;rsquo;s no point in that:
Future&amp;lt;Socket&amp;gt; future = executor.submit( Listeners.createListener( PORT ) ); try { Socket socket = future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kafka tips &amp; tricks</title>
      <link>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/2018/06/24/kafka-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/2018/06/24/kafka-tips/</guid>
      <description>Список консьюмер-групп
docker run wurstmeister/kafka /opt/kafka/bin/kafka-consumer-groups.sh --bootstrap-server kafka:9092 --list  Информация по консьюмер-группе
docker run wurstmeister/kafka /opt/kafka/bin/kafka-consumer-groups.sh --bootstrap-server kafka:9092 --group id1 --describe  Установка оффсета на начало
docker run wurstmeister/kafka /opt/kafka/bin/kafka-consumer-groups.sh --bootstrap-server kafka:9092 --topic topic --group id1 --reset-offsets --to-earliest --execute  Установка оффсета на конец
docker run wurstmeister/kafka /opt/kafka/bin/kafka-consumer-groups.sh --bootstrap-server kafka:9092 --topic topic --group id1 --reset-offsets --to-latest --execute  Установка оффсета на дату-время
docker run wurstmeister/kafka /opt/kafka/bin/kafka-consumer-groups.sh --bootstrap-server kafka:9092 --topic topic --group id1 --reset-offsets --to-datetime &amp;quot;2017-12-22T00:00:00.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Encrypt with lego and Nginx</title>
      <link>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/2018/06/24/lego-nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/2018/06/24/lego-nginx/</guid>
      <description>xenolf/lego it&amp;rsquo;s a feature-rich Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt client and ACME library written in Go.
1. Prepare Nginx server
server { listen 80 default; server_name example.org www.example.org; location /.well-known/acme-challenge { proxy_pass http://127.0.0.1:81; proxy_set_header Host $host; } # Other directives }  2. Update ca-certificates for CentOS 5 (optional)
Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt CA certificate is not included into root CA bundle of old Linux distributions like RHEL/Centos 5. You have to replace this bundle manually with fresh one from cURL website:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Запуск контейнеров с помощью Fig</title>
      <link>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/2018/06/24/docker-fig/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/2018/06/24/docker-fig/</guid>
      <description>Это третья статья цикла Building test environments with Docker.
Как мы уже убедились, запуск контейнеров с помощью docker run — занятие весьма муторное, т.к. необходимо указывать множество опций. При запуске же нескольких контейнеров ситуация только ухудшается, т.к. теперь нужно задавать имена и линки.
Эту проблему решает инструмент Fig, который может запустить/остановить целое тестовое окружение, состоящее из набора контейнеров. Описание контейнеров задано в YAML-файле. Таким образом, этот YAML-файл представляет собой конфигурацию тестового окружения.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Подготовка и запуск docker-контейнеров</title>
      <link>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/2015/01/04/docker-prepare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 13:49:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/2015/01/04/docker-prepare/</guid>
      <description>Это первая статья цикла Building test environments with Docker.
Сразу оговорюсь, что все docker-контейнеры основаны на baseimage-docker. Этот образ позволяет запускать в контейнере несколько приложений с помощью супервизора runit и содержит ssh, cron, syslog &amp;ldquo;из коробки&amp;rdquo;.
Хотя подобный подход не рекомендуется разработчиками Docker, он очень удобен в эксплуатации и не принуждает разработчика к своему &amp;ldquo;proper way&amp;rdquo;. Всегда можно использовать канонический подход от Docker с volumes и nsenter, а, при желании, подключаться к контейнерам по ssh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First note</title>
      <link>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/2014/07/28/oldest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/2014/07/28/oldest/</guid>
      <description>This blog is based on Hugo - static site generator written on Go. GitHub interaction is organized with use of Hosting on GitHub Pages tutorial. See &amp;ldquo;Configure git Workflow&amp;rdquo; section specifically.
And for all of the git 1.7.x (and older) users - you can grab git-subtree from contrib directory of Git repo. I&amp;rsquo;ve used git-subtree from latest 1.8.x. It&amp;rsquo;s just a shell script, run make, chmod +x git-subtree and copy it to /usr/lib/git-core.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>