<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Pavel Derendyaev test</title>
    <link>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Pavel Derendyaev test</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 19:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.dddpaul.pw/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker network and Swarm mode links</title>
      <link>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/2018/06/24/docker-network-swarm-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/2018/06/24/docker-network-swarm-links/</guid>
      <description>Some useful articles &amp;amp; videos about modern networking in Docker:
 Macvlan Driver - Docker Macvlan driver is out of experimental in Docker 1.12. Configuring Macvlan and Ipvlan Linux Networking - What Docker Macvlan driver does under the hood. Materials for 2016 DevOps Networking Forum (DNF) Presentation - Slides about Docker networking with Ansible playbooks. Видео докладов с Docker митапа - Особо интересен доклад Константина Назарова &amp;ldquo;Каждому контейнеру по IP&amp;rdquo; (на русском).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker registry on Centos 7</title>
      <link>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/2018/06/24/docker-registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dddpaul.pw/2018/06/24/docker-registry/</guid>
      <description>1. Create logical volumes for direct-lvm production mode
Assume that we have 40 GByte block device named as /dev/sdb with one full-size Linux partition on it.
Official Device Mapper storage driver guide recommends to use thin pools now. Use these commands to create thin-provisioned logical volumes:
pvcreate /dev/sdb1 # Create physical volume vgcreate docker /dev/sdb1 # Create volume group and add this physical volume to it # Create logical volumes lvcreate --wipesignatures y -n data docker -l 40%VG lvcreate --wipesignatures y -n registry docker -l 40%VG lvcreate --wipesignatures y -n metadata docker -l 2%VG # Convert data volume to thin pool&amp;#39;s data volume lvconvert -y --zero n -c 512K --thinpool docker/data --poolmetadata docker/metadata # Set thin pool autoextend features cat &amp;gt; /etc/lvm/profile/docker-data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>